Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License

License Notes

This is an acceptable license you can use for contributing content to this field guide.

This license is very similar to the CC BY-SA license we recommend but it lacks the requirement that another party using the content as part of a derivative work use the identical license.

This is the license used for all written content within this field guide and for the bulk of the non-text resources.

CC BY 4.0 Authoritative Canonical Source: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode

CC BY 4.0 Human Readable Summary: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/

By exercising the Licensed Rights (defined below), You accept and agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License ("Public License"). To the extent this Public License may be interpreted as a contract, You are granted the Licensed Rights in consideration of Your acceptance of these terms and conditions, and the Licensor grants You such rights in consideration of benefits the Licensor receives from making the Licensed Material available under these terms and conditions.

Section 1 - Definitions.

Adapted Material means material subject to Copyright and Similar Rights that is derived from or based upon the Licensed Material and in which the Licensed Material is translated, altered, arranged, transformed, or otherwise modified in a manner requiring permission under the Copyright and Similar Rights held by the Licensor. For purposes of this Public License, where the Licensed Material is a musical work, performance, or sound recording, Adapted Material is always produced where the Licensed Material is synched in timed relation with a moving image.
Adapter's License means the license You apply to Your Copyright and Similar Rights in Your contributions to Adapted Material in accordance with the terms and conditions of this Public License.
Copyright and Similar Rights means copyright and/or similar rights closely related to copyright including, without limitation, performance, broadcast, sound recording, and Sui Generis Database Rights, without regard to how the rights are labeled or categorized. For purposes of this Public License, the rights specified in Section 2(b)(1)-(2) are not Copyright and Similar Rights.
Effective Technological Measures means those measures that, in the absence of proper authority, may not be circumvented under laws fulfilling obligations under Article 11 of the WIPO Copyright Treaty adopted on December 20, 1996, and/or similar international agreements.
Exceptions and Limitations means fair use, fair dealing, and/or any other exception or limitation to Copyright and Similar Rights that applies to Your use of the Licensed Material.
Licensed Material means the artistic or literary work, database, or other material to which the Licensor applied this Public License.
Licensed Rights means the rights granted to You subject to the terms and conditions of this Public License, which are limited to all Copyright and Similar Rights that apply to Your use of the Licensed Material and that the Licensor has authority to license.
Licensor means the individual(s) or entity(ies) granting rights under this Public License.
Share means to provide material to the public by any means or process that requires permission under the Licensed Rights, such as reproduction, public display, public performance, distribution, dissemination, communication, or importation, and to make material available to the public including in ways that members of the public may access the material from a place and at a time individually chosen by them.
Sui Generis Database Rights means to provide material to the public by any means or process that requires permission under the Licensed Rights, such as reproduction, public display, public performance, distribution, dissemination, communication, or importation, and to make material available to the public including in ways that members of the public may access the material from a place and at a time individually chosen by them.
You means the individual or entity exercising the Licensed Rights under this Public License. Your has a corresponding meaning.

Section 2 - Scope.

License grant.

Subject to the terms and conditions of this Public License, the Licensor hereby grants You a worldwide, royalty-free, non-sublicensable, non-exclusive, irrevocable license to exercise the Licensed Rights in the Licensed Material to:

reproduce and Share the Licensed Material, in whole or in part; and
produce, reproduce, and Share Adapted Material.

Exceptions and Limitations. For the avoidance of doubt, where Exceptions and Limitations apply to Your use, this Public License does not apply, and You do not need to comply with its terms and conditions.
Term. The term of this Public License is specified in Section 6(a).
Media and formats; technical modifications allowed. The Licensor authorizes You to exercise the Licensed Rights in all media and formats whether now known or hereafter created, and to make technical modifications necessary to do so. The Licensor waives and/or agrees not to assert any right or authority to forbid You from making technical modifications necessary to exercise the Licensed Rights, including technical modifications necessary to circumvent Effective Technological Measures. For purposes of this Public License, simply making modifications authorized by this Section 2(a)(4) never produces Adapted Material.
Downstream recipients.

Offer from the Licensor – Licensed Material. Every recipient of the Licensed Material automatically receives an offer from the Licensor to exercise the Licensed Rights under the terms and conditions of this Public License.
No downstream restrictions. You may not offer or impose any additional or different terms or conditions on, or apply any Effective Technological Measures to, the Licensed Material if doing so restricts exercise of the Licensed Rights by any recipient of the Licensed Material.

No endorsement. Nothing in this Public License constitutes or may be construed as permission to assert or imply that You are, or that Your use of the Licensed Material is, connected with, or sponsored, endorsed, or granted official status by, the Licensor or others designated to receive attribution as provided in Section 3(a)(1)(A)(i).

Other rights.

Moral rights, such as the right of integrity, are not licensed under this Public License, nor are publicity, privacy, and/or other similar personality rights; however, to the extent possible, the Licensor waives and/or agrees not to assert any such rights held by the Licensor to the limited extent necessary to allow You to exercise the Licensed Rights, but not otherwise.
Patent and trademark rights are not licensed under this Public License.
To the extent possible, the Licensor waives any right to collect royalties from You for the exercise of the Licensed Rights, whether directly or through a collecting society under any voluntary or waivable statutory or compulsory licensing scheme. In all other cases the Licensor expressly reserves any right to collect such royalties.

Section 3 - License Conditions.

Your exercise of the Licensed Rights is expressly made subject to the following conditions.

Attribution.

If You Share the Licensed Material (including in modified form), You must:

retain the following if it is supplied by the Licensor with the Licensed Material:

identification of the creator(s) of the Licensed Material and any others designated to receive attribution, in any reasonable manner requested by the Licensor (including by pseudonym if designated);
a copyright notice;
a notice that refers to this Public License;
a notice that refers to the disclaimer of warranties;
a URI or hyperlink to the Licensed Material to the extent reasonably practicable;

indicate if You modified the Licensed Material and retain an indication of any previous modifications; and
indicate the Licensed Material is licensed under this Public License, and include the text of, or the URI or hyperlink to, this Public License.

You may satisfy the conditions in Section 3(a)(1) in any reasonable manner based on the medium, means, and context in which You Share the Licensed Material. For example, it may be reasonable to satisfy the conditions by providing a URI or hyperlink to a resource that includes the required information.
If requested by the Licensor, You must remove any of the information required by Section 3(a)(1)(A) to the extent reasonably practicable.
If You Share Adapted Material You produce, the Adapter's License You apply must not prevent recipients of the Adapted Material from complying with this Public License.

Section 4 - Sui Generis Database Rights.

Where the Licensed Rights include Sui Generis Database Rights that apply to Your use of the Licensed Material:

for the avoidance of doubt, Section 2(a)(1) grants You the right to extract, reuse, reproduce, and Share all or a substantial portion of the contents of the database;
if You include all or a substantial portion of the database contents in a database in which You have Sui Generis Database Rights, then the database in which You have Sui Generis Database Rights (but not its individual contents) is Adapted Material; and
You must comply with the conditions in Section 3(a) if You Share all or a substantial portion of the contents of the database.

For the avoidance of doubt, this Section 4 supplements and does not replace Your obligations under this Public License where the Licensed Rights include other Copyright and Similar Rights.

Section 5 - Disclaimer of Warranties and Limitation of Liability.

Unless otherwise separately undertaken by the Licensor, to the extent possible, the Licensor offers the Licensed Material as-is and as-available, and makes no representations or warranties of any kind concerning the Licensed Material, whether express, implied, statutory, or other. This includes, without limitation, warranties of title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, non-infringement, absence of latent or other defects, accuracy, or the presence or absence of errors, whether or not known or discoverable. Where disclaimers of warranties are not allowed in full or in part, this disclaimer may not apply to You.
To the extent possible, in no event will the Licensor be liable to You on any legal theory (including, without limitation, negligence) or otherwise for any direct, special, indirect, incidental, consequential, punitive, exemplary, or other losses, costs, expenses, or damages arising out of this Public License or use of the Licensed Material, even if the Licensor has been advised of the possibility of such losses, costs, expenses, or damages. Where a limitation of liability is not allowed in full or in part, this limitation may not apply to You.
The disclaimer of warranties and limitation of liability provided above shall be interpreted in a manner that, to the extent possible, most closely approximates an absolute disclaimer and waiver of all liability.

Section 6 - Term and Termination.

This Public License applies for the term of the Copyright and Similar Rights licensed here. However, if You fail to comply with this Public License, then Your rights under this Public License terminate automatically.
Where Your right to use the Licensed Material has terminated under Section 6(a), it reinstates:

automatically as of the date the violation is cured, provided it is cured within 30 days of Your discovery of the violation; or
upon express reinstatement by the Licensor.

For the avoidance of doubt, this Section 6(b) does not affect any right the Licensor may have to seek remedies for Your violations of this Public License.
For the avoidance of doubt, the Licensor may also offer the Licensed Material under separate terms or conditions or stop distributing the Licensed Material at any time; however, doing so will not terminate this Public License.
Sections 1, 5, 6, 7, and 8 survive termination of this Public License.

Section 7 - Other Terms and Conditions.

The Licensor shall not be bound by any additional or different terms or conditions communicated by You unless expressly agreed.
Any arrangements, understandings, or agreements regarding the Licensed Material not stated herein are separate from and independent of the terms and conditions of this Public License.

Section 8 - Interpretation.

For the avoidance of doubt, this Public License does not, and shall not be interpreted to, reduce, limit, restrict, or impose conditions on any use of the Licensed Material that could lawfully be made without permission under this Public License.
To the extent possible, if any provision of this Public License is deemed unenforceable, it shall be automatically reformed to the minimum extent necessary to make it enforceable. If the provision cannot be reformed, it shall be severed from this Public License without affecting the enforceability of the remaining terms and conditions.
To the extent possible, if any provision of this Public License is deemed unenforceable, it shall be automatically reformed to the minimum extent necessary to make it enforceable. If the provision cannot be reformed, it shall be severed from this Public License without affecting the enforceability of the remaining terms and conditions.
Nothing in this Public License constitutes or may be interpreted as a limitation upon, or waiver of, any privileges and immunities that apply to the Licensor or You, including from the legal processes of any jurisdiction or authority.

Creative Commons is not a party to its public licenses. Notwithstanding, Creative Commons may elect to apply one of its public licenses to material it publishes and in those instances will be considered the “Licensor.” The text of the Creative Commons public licenses is dedicated to the public domain under the CC0 Public Domain Dedication. Except for the limited purpose of indicating that material is shared under a Creative Commons public license or as otherwise permitted by the Creative Commons policies published at creativecommons.org/policies, Creative Commons does not authorize the use of the trademark “Creative Commons” or any other trademark or logo of Creative Commons without its prior written consent including, without limitation, in connection with any unauthorized modifications to any of its public licenses or any other arrangements, understandings, or agreements concerning use of licensed material. For the avoidance of doubt, this paragraph does not form part of the public licenses.

Creative Commons may be contacted at creativecommons.org.

Pixabay License

At one point in time, Pixabay used the CC0 license for all images and videos uploaded to their site.

Once they had a rather significant number of images, they silently changed the usage license to their own. Bait and Switch cow manure.

The new license is only compatible with use in the CC BY-SA field guide if the following conditions are met:

Only still image photographic content is used.
No people are used in the image. This satisfies restriction c.
No products, brands, or trademarks are used in the image. This satisfies restriction d.
The image is modified in such a manner that it is readily visually different from the image as it appears on Pixabay. Cropping the image meets that requirement. This helps satisfy restriction a and restriction b.
The largest side of the image is not more than 2048 pixels and the smallest side of the image is not more than 1024 pixels. This helps satisfy restriction a and restriction b.

Use of Pixabay content is discouraged but Content Curators for this field guide are allowed to use images from Pixabay when suitable content is not available from a CC BY-SA, CC BY, CC0, or Verifiable Public Domain source as long as the above guidelines are met.

However Content Curators are encouraged to attempt contact the photographer to both get the real name of the photographer and explicit permission outside the context of Pixabay to use the image under the terms of the CC BY-SA license.

Pixabay License Authoritative Canonical Source: https://pixabay.com/service/terms/#license

Pixabay does not version their license. The license as reproduced below is archived at https://web.archive.org/web/20200218210632/https://pixabay.com/service/terms/.

License for Images and Videos – Pixabay License

Images and Videos on Pixabay are made available under the Pixabay License on the following terms. Under the Pixabay License you are granted an irrevocable, worldwide, non-exclusive and royalty free right to use, download, copy, modify or adapt the Images and Videos for commercial or non-commercial purposes. Attribution of the photographer or Pixabay is not required but is always appreciated.

The Pixabay License does not allow:

sale or distribution of Images or Videos as digital stock photos or as digital wallpapers;
sale or distribution of Images or Videos e.g. as a posters, digital prints or physical products, without adding any additional elements or otherwise adding value;
depiction of identifiable persons in an offensive, pornographic, obscene, immoral, defamatory or libelous way; or
any suggestion that there is an endorsement of products and services by depicted persons, brands, and organisations, unless permission was granted.

Please be aware that while all Images and Videos on Pixabay are free to use for commercial and non-commercial purposes, depicted items in the Images or Videos, such as identifiable people, logos, brands, etc. may be subject to additional copyrights, property rights, privacy rights, trademarks etc. and may require the consent of a third party or the license of these rights - particularly for commercial applications. Pixabay does not represent or warrant that such consents or licenses have been obtained, and expressly disclaims any liability in this respect.

NOTE: These terms have not yet been reviewed by a lawyer. Changes are likely when that happens.

Redistribution Conditions

This Creative Work is distributed under the terms and conditions of the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License.

If you wish to redistribute the ePub file containing this work, without modification, you may do so for free or for profit without needing to provide any royalties or compensation.

If you wish to modify this work or redistribute part of it, please read what follows.

Definitions

Pipfrosch Press at this time is not an actual legal entity. Until such time that it is, it refers to Michael A. Peters, the arrogant bastard visionary behind this project.
The Complete Work refers to the ePub file with the ePub unique-identifier of c0957b2a-f6e8-4105-842e-2ab89264e978 whether or not there is an associated ISBN identifier.
The OPF File refers to the OEBPS/content.opf file within the ePub archive.
The Title Page refers to the file OEBPS/TitlePage.xhtml file within the ePub archive.
The Complete ToC refers to the file OEBPS/TOC.xhtml file within the ePub archive. Even though it is an XHTML file, it is not referenced in The OPF File <spine> node. It exists as metadata for ePub viewers.
Metadata Files include the following:

The OPF File.
The Complete ToC.
All contents of the META-INF directory within the ePub archive.
All files listet within The OPF File <manifest> node that specifically have a media-type="text/xml" attribute.

Font Files includes all files listed within The OPF File <manifest> node that specifically have a media-type attribute value of font/ttf, font/otf, font/woff, or font/woff2.
Functional Code Files refers to the collection of all files listed within The OPF File <manifest> node that specifically have a media-type="text/css" or a media-type="application/javascript" attribute.
License Files refers to all files within the OEBPS/licenses directory.
The Creative Work refers to the collection of all files listed within The OPF File <manifest> node that are not Metadata Files, Font Files, Functional Code Files, or License Files.
Text Creative Resource refers to any file that is part of The Creative Work and is listed in the <manifest> node of The OPF File using a media-type="application/xhtml+xml" attribute.
Non-Text Creative Resource refers to any file that is part of The Creative Work and is listed in the <manifest> node of The OPF File using a media-type attribute other than application/xhtml+xml.
Scientific Reviewer refers to a scientist that has reviewed specific content for scientific accuracy.
Content Curator refers to an approved person or team working on behalf of Pipfrosch Press to ensure the itellectual and factual quality of content included within The Creative Content.

The Creative Work

The Creative Work is ©2020 Pipfrosch Press and is released under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License (CC BY-SA 4.0).

If you are distributing a modified version of The Creative Work, you must follow the terms of that license.

When modifying a Text Creative Resource that has been reviewed by a Scientific Reviewer, reference to the Scientific Reviewer must be removed as the review no longer applies to the modified content.

If you are distributing a modified version of The Creative Work, you also must ensure you comply with the conditions described in the sections of this document titled The OPF File and The Title Page.

If you are distributing a modified version of The Creative Work that includes the License Files, you also must ensure you comply with the conditions described in the sections of this document titled License Files.

If you are distributing a modified version of The Creative Work that includes the Font Files that are part of The Complete Work, you must also comply with the license(s) that applies to those Font Files, see the section titled Font Files.

Metadata Files

All Metadata Files are licensed under the Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0) license (effectively you have the same right as if they were Public Domain).

Functional Code Files

All Functional Code Files are licensed under the Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0) license (effectively you have the same right as if they were Public Domain).

Font Files

Intel® Clear Sans was chosen for this project because Michael A. Peters, who has some reading disabilities including but not limited to an increased liklihood of epileptic seizures when his eyes get tired, found Intel® Clear Sans to be exceptionally easy to read on small screen devices compared with the default fonts that many ePub viewers use.

The Intel® Clear Sans fonts are released by Intel® under the terms of the Apache License, Version 2.0.

Original versions of the Clear Sans Font Files were obtained from https://01.org/clear-sans. Modified versions of those files are included in The Complete Work:

ClearSans-Regular-wlatin.ttf
ClearSans-Italic-wlatin.ttf
ClearSans-Bold-wlatin.ttf
ClearSans-BoldItalic-wlatin.ttf

The original Font Files were modified to remove glyphs that are not needed outside the context of Western Latin content, thus significantly reducing the size of the files (this is called Font Subsetting and is a common publishing production practice for embedded fonts).

Additionally, Michael A. Peters created four Font Files to compliment Intel® Clear Sans. Work on those Font Files is not yet complete, but is complete enough to use here. They also are released under the terms of the Apache License, Version 2.0:

ClearSansSCP.ttf
ClearSansSCP-Italic.ttf
ClearSansSCP-Bold.ttf
ClearSansSCP-BoldItalic.ttf

At this time, no other Font Files are used in The Complete Work.

License Files

With the exception of this file (Redistribution_Conditions.xhtml), every file within the OEBPS/licenses directory contains license content written by a third party license creator, but wrapped in XHTML markup for proper rendering within an ePub book.

The License Files should be considered CC0 however, including this file, you may not alter them in such a way that the license and/or terms are mis-represented.

The OPF File

When distributing modified versions of The Complete Work that include an OPF file, whether or not it was derived from The OPF File used within The Complete Work, the following conditions must be met:

If an ISBN code is present within The OPF File and/or on The Title Page, you must remove it before distributing a modified version of The Creative Work. You can of course use your own ISBN if you so choose.

You must not use the same unique-identifier within your OPF file.

You must not specify Pipfrosch Press within the <dc:publisher> node or otherwise indicate that Pipfrosch Press is the publisher.

You must have appropriate <dc:author> and <dc:contributor> nodes, along with the appropriate marc:relators <meta> nodes within your OPF <metadata> node, for any of the creative content from The Creative Work that you retained.

Those metadata tags are part of the proper attribution required for CC BY-SA 4.0 compliance.

OPF File Content Curator Exception

Content Curators and Pipfrosch Press approved content authors working under the authority of a Content Curator do not need to worry about changing the unique-identifier or changing the <dc:publisher> node but the version of this work they are working on must not contain an ISBN code.

OPF File Accessibility Rights

Libraries, Schools, or other institutions who need to modify this work for the explicit purpose of providing missing accessibility needs for a user with a disability are explicitly allowed to do so without needing to worry about removing the ISBN code, changing the unique-identifier, or changing the <dc:publisher> node.

It is requested that the accessibility issue be brought to the attention of Pipfrosch Press so the issue can be addressed in a future version, or at a minimum so that we can update the schema:accessibilityHazard <meta> node, but no such requirement for contact is made.

Regardless of whether or you not you contact Pipfrosch Press about the accessibility issue, you have our thanks for helping to reduce an accessibility barrier for someone who wishes to access the content.

The Title Page

When distributing modified versions of The Complete Work or The Creative Work, take special care with the title page of your derivative work. The following conditions must be met:

The title of the modified work must differ.

Pipfrosch Press must not be indicated as the publisher.

Pipfrosch Press ISBN codes must not be used.

In compiance with the CC BY-SA 4.0 license, the title of The Creative Work must be specified as the original work that has been modified and Pipfrosch Press MUST be prominently referenced as the creator of the original work that has been modified.

Title Page Content Curator Exception

Content Curators and Pipfrosch Press approved content authors working under the authority of a Content Curator do not need to worry about changing the title or publisher but the version of this work they are working on must not contain an ISBN code.

Title Page Accessibility Rights

Libraries, Schools, or other institutions who need to modify this work for the explicit purpose of providing missing accessibility needs for a user with a disability are explicitly allowed to do so without needing to worry about changing the title, publisher, or removing the ISBN code from The Title Page.

Individual File Modification and Redistribution

Any Text Creative Resource may be redistributed with or without modification under the terms of the CC BY-SA 4.0 license.

When modifying a Text Creative Resource that has been reviewed by a Scientific Reviewer, reference to the Scientific Reviewer must be removed as the review no longer applies to the modified content.

Any Non-Text Creative Resource may be redistributed with or without modification under the terms of the CC BY-SA 4.0 license but in some cases may also be redistributed under the terms of a different license.

Each Non-Text Creative Resource will have an accompanying metadata file of the same file name except using a .xml file extension. These Metadata Files will include the relevant license for the resource, which will be one of the following licenses:

Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License
Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported
Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License
Creative Commons CC0 1.0 Universal
Pixabay License
Public Domain

Good Faith

None of the conditions specified in this documented are intended to conflict with Good Faith re-use and/or modification of The Creative Work. The CC BY-SA 4.0 license was specifically selected to allow Good Faith re-use and/or modification of The Creative Work.

IN THE EVENT ANY OF THESE TERMS CONFLICT WITH YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE TERMS OF THE CC BY-SA 4.0 LICENSE, THE TERMS OF THAT LICENSE TAKE PRECEDENCE.